hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft we are
on episode
what episode are we on
hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft and i
think we're in like episode 28 now the
green head hunt has been in full swing
i've actually still got a few of mine
around the base here some people have
actually been in the base but i keep
adding more and more to the game because
there actually have been a lot taken and
oh what's this
there's a okay i i think something fishy
oh is this stress monster i think
something fishy is going on because
she's got that kind of accent did you
lose your head i have returned them to
you you're welcome stress ah sweet she
has no idea that there's a competition
going on so i think the only logical
thing to do here is to go and put them
straight back in her base
so this is stress monsters
ice kingdom thing going on here so
i think if we can find a little room
maybe not this one is a bit too big
she clearly hasn't been in this one
though
maybe this is this looks like her normal
base yep this looks like it so if we
just put them all in here wait is that a
chicken head is stress poultry man maybe
it's poultry woman
anyway let's go and put them all in
here there we go i've put them all back
in her base and it says green heads are
never lost they're only found
i think that's pretty neat hopefully
she'll get the message that there's
actually a competition on i bet as soon
as her episode goes out she's gonna find
out from the comments that there is a
competition going on
so you may also notice when i was flying
out my base
that i've added the giant rings that i
was talking about last episode and i
called it a very stupid thing but i've
managed to do it i've also
lit up most of the c4 and i was actually
singing the pickles on the seafloor song
i've done quite a lot of it man it takes
a lot i think that was like
20 odd stacks of pickles down there it
takes a long time to light all that up
but doesn't it look awesome and this
ring doesn't this ring look absolutely
brilliant now i actually time-lapsed the
creation of this
because i want to show you quickly just
how much i messed up it's so difficult
to make this kind of ring so what i did
was i went on to oh my goodness
oh my goodness this is dangerous
i need to make that mob farm because
my base is so good for mobs let's go and
sleep so basically let me explain this
is the time lapse going on right now so
making a giant circle in minecraft
absolute nightmare because it's so easy
to mess up one block at a place and the
whole thing doesn't line up very very
bad so i obviously had a few attempts at
it it took me over an hour to make those
two rings and it took a lot of resources
as well and if you didn't know we've got
a new nether base project i know i'm
kind of going off on a tangent here but
it's kind of important so we're making
this mini map of the entire server in
the nether and it is absolutely massive
we need thousands and thousands of
blocks but we also need thousands and
thousands of blocks of the ones that i
get regularly sand gravel terracotta all
of those kind of blocks so i kind of
have to weigh up whether i contribute a
lot to that or i focus here on what i've
got to do because i use like several
stacks i use dozens of stacks of
terracotta just to make these two rings
making all that filled with concrete and
then the walls underwater we're talking
thousands of blocks and of course i
should really play my part as best i can
in the nether hub project as well
but as you can see the rings are pretty
much complete now so i messed up a few
times but overall it was pretty good now
even if you're you're thinking that this
doesn't look like a proper circle
because of like all this janky stuff
going on here i admit it does look janky
but i used world edit on a different
server to give me the precise radius of
this circle so this is a computer
generated circle and it is pixel perfect
as well as pixel perfect perfect as it
can be so it might look is slightly
different to how the circle would look
if i did it by eye
but this looks pretty cool so basically
because my base is so tall and thin
i thought that it needed a bit of a base
width addition to it and my goodness
doesn't that look rad that ring really
cements it in place now
there's a lot of work to be done here a
lot of work
and i won't be making another aquarium i
don't think because that took way longer
than it needed to but i probably will
put at least one wall maybe on the
outside but in this side of the base you
can see that i've got this glass here
and this is a really cool addition but
it's all white concrete on this ring so
i'm thinking that i probably will put
some glass panes there or glass panels
so that you can see down into the bottom
and i think that's going to be really
cool so that is the next part of the
base i feel like i haven't done enough
bass progress recently so i'm going to
really focus today on making a lot of
things for the base and one of the
things that i want to do today is move
my nether portal so at the moment my
nether portal is all the way down here
so that's where it is there and it's not
really in a very neat location so what
i'm going to do is i'm going to travel
all the way up to the top here and i've
got a couple of ideas
so i'm probably going to show you in a
different world but there's a big space
here and this is where i want my nether
portal to be hopefully i've got enough
resources i've got some obsidian and
some blocks of iron now i'm either
thinking well i'll tell you what i'll
show you in the other world
so here we have our backup world this is
my base and wow it feels weird to be
able to just fly around in creative like
this so i'm thinking the portal should
go up here there's this really nice
space for something extra special
the problem that i'm having here is that
this is not a convenient place
to use a portal maybe it could just be
ceremonial but let's let's put this into
practice right so all of my stuff is
down here at the bottom so
everything that i use is down here
from my chests to the
smelter to the farms everything i use is
down here simply because it's a pain to
go up all the time
so that's why i have this elevator so if
i wanted to go into the nether i have to
wait a full 20 seconds to make it all
the way up to the top
man
really is a long way and this doesn't
even go to the top anymore it goes to
here so
yeah this is a really long way to go to
just use the nether portal
so i'm thinking maybe this is the guest
one and then i have a more convenient
one so if anyone comes to my base the
portal will end up here but then i could
use the one down there i
it's very very difficult to get right
nevertheless i think that we should use
this space up here for the nether portal
as i think it will look really really
rad
there's two things that i have in mind
for this there's two options and both of
them are spherical in nature
we have a height of 29 blocks and i
don't want it to hit the actual top
because that will ruin the effect of the
pillars so i'm going to remove that and
we don't want it to touch this so we
we're looking at about that big now that
perhaps doesn't look too large that is
12 blocks
so if i sit roughly in the middle here
and i type in this command
here we have a sphere of blue glass
now my idea is to have a glass earth
replica at the top now that does not
look big at all
in context
that looks absolutely tiny
might have to make that significantly
bigger in fact i'm starting to think
that this one won't work at all but
we'll we'll persevere nonetheless
so i've moved it slightly up with a
sphere of 11. that actually does look
pretty good because it's actually
floating now
but this is where the base is usually
viewed from that could be pretty decent
now how would this look with a portal
there we go so we do a big portal
and i can kind of work with this i can
either make this like
just another portal here
by doing that i can make it seem like
it's all filled in or i could just keep
it with that in mind
so if we have a look from the outside
that's what it might look like it's the
earth portal but obviously i need to put
a little bit more earth in here because
right now it's a planet full of water
but you kind of get the concept all
we're trying to do here is this is not
accurate to how it would
particularly be but you get the concept
it would be an earth
floating above the giant base and i
gotta admit it does look pretty cool
uh as long as you could figure out what
it is because it definitely needs more
green in there but it does definitely
work however there's a second idea that
i want to show you now for this one i'm
actually gonna have to start this off
with a big old rectangle there we go
i've got a big old rectangle and this is
where my next portal idea comes from now
all i'm going to do
just for the sake of this demonstration
this might not be exactly how it ends up
being decorated but what i'm going to do
is essentially try and build a circle
around this to make it look like a
stargate
because i'm going for a very futuristic
build here
i really want to try and keep it in
theme as much as possible
the hard part
is trying to make this circular
while maintaining this giant square so
that's going to be the challenge here
but i'm pretty sure i can make it work
if i put my mind to it
okay so that's not too bad i've managed
to put together something that looks a
bit like a circle the more you zoom out
the more the further you get away the
less of a circle it starts to look
however that looks pretty good and i'm
also thinking if i turn that into quartz
i can use some slabs and staircases as
well so let's actually put in the
portals you can see the purple and let's
just uh and let me just say right now
that this is undecorated this is just a
proof of concept
something like that that makes it seem a
bit more clean as still not a perfect
circle but those are kind of the two
options we're talking about i do like
that portal in a huge amount and i can
just picture it now with a few
decorations like some trapdoors on the
sides maybe a bit of an indent here an
indent there
this could work really really well i
could even make it supported but i kind
of like the idea that it sort of just
floats here in the middle
there's something else i can do here but
those are the two basic concepts that i
have to show you so let's take a proper
look back here
not gonna lie it kinda looks like a
flower
maybe i shouldn't put a portal there at
all take a look at the card section here
i'm gonna put three options in
for the world design for this stargate
design or no design at all leave it
empty those are the three options that
we have
and
i will take your guys opinion into
account but i'm very much undecided
so i'm not sure which one i'm gonna go
for yet but i have just challenged ren
to a rocket fight and by rocket fight i
mean i'm challenging him
to
a flight contest and this should be
really funny i've obviously been
practicing my flying a lot so let's go
and find ren he should be around here so
there he is
hello hello
are you ready to take on my challenge um
not really
i've seen you flying around here dude it
it's
pretty impressive
well i'm not always the best so this is
this is how it's going to go down right
the goal here is all you've got to do is
follow me until i decide we're at the
end and if you get to the end you win a
prize
okay
right if you die
you don't okay
um
all right i want to even the playing
field though oh no armor
get it off no um well to be fair yeah
okay
i'm gonna i'm gonna plop everything
i have in here yep decent plop i
literally have an elytra some rockets
and some chicken that's it right
i've got some steak and some rockets
there you go there's there's some
rockets you might need yeah you might
need that many there we go
so you're gonna have to follow me
including the take-off
okay where we're taking off from here
i'm going to jump up straight up
straight off of here and we're going to
go on a journey are you ready
ah
this is
ugh i can just feel the shame already
if i die you win
okay we're going to start off fairly
easy going through some simple holes
yeah we're going to weave
yeah
oh oh okay i took i took a hit i took a
hit i'm back weave again
all right all right just follow me from
here are you ready this is where it's
going to start getting intense
where did you even die
well that that was embarrassing what did
you hear i didn't i
found a rocket
yeah
i didn't even make it into the valley
i don't even know where you wherever you
oh yeah i see it
yeah i splattered right into the side of
the mountain
as i told you my dude this is not this
is not my jam all right so what we're
going to do is we're going to give you
some armor
and i won't have armor oh okay
all right there's all your stuff in the
bottom take my okay as well
and we're going to take this down from
150 cc mario kart to 50cc mario kart
okay okay
are you ready
you didn't even get to my base okay so
we're going to do the same route i'm
going to go through this little gap in
scars world war ii hangar
yeah and then we're going to fly through
the chimneys
turn
fly through the chimneys yeah did it oh
doing it in third person is way easier
we're going to go through the middle of
this
okay take some damage i'm fine okay okay
and now we're going to go through the
middle of the mumbo and duke statues do
a hard right
okay through the mumbo and juke statues
do a hard right yep yeah that's it and
then through the chorus fruit up through
the chorus fruit
okay kind of
all right cool and then we're going to
go right we're going to do a swift
maneuver now we're going to go into
false's fishbowl and then straight back
out again
oh geez okay
in and out
oh god nice okay cool
right
now we're gonna go and see how how you
can do the dive so
we're gonna maneuver through these trees
yeah hard left
okay we're gonna go to my base we're
gonna go all the way up to the top
okay
yep
my heart's racing right now i don't know
why park over slowly
and through the tunnel we go
oh
okay
all right we're gonna go through scars
trees now and then we're gonna go to
this volcano
okay
yeah here we go
oh my goodness
okay
did you make it
yep and then we're gonna go through his
portal
hard right
through the portal you've done this too
long dude you know exactly the roots
come on through here in this little hole
round round around the core a couple of
times oh here we go yes and then out the
other side then out the other side then
we're gonna go to
all right now you're gonna have to try
and keep up because we're gonna go and
do some heavy maneuvering oh i took a
bit of damage
are you doing some bobbing and weaving
okay
and then what we're gonna do is we're
gonna go through the concord
oh that's disgusting and then we're
gonna go through this hole here through
the trees round the mountain we're gonna
go around scars lovely landscaping shop
a couple of times because this is a
great place to go
gonna bob weave go around
this is like a server tour on red bull
yeah
all right so here's the last test here's
the last test okay yeah so this is the
hardest maneuver because of the angles
you've got to dive into the pickle shop
and then all the way to the bottom and
then straight back out again
into the pickle shop all the way into
the bottom and then all the way straight
back up again
did it quite make it and uh i kind of
made it i took a lot of damage
i died in your pickle dude
this is an awkward moment
i didn't even die from flying
i just fell to my death
oh
i missed the water
tgg unit gg my dude
that was a lot of fun thank you very
much ren and if anyone else wants to
challenge me at my rocket game then i
would love to do a bit more flying
however i'm really hoping that someone's
going to make a actual flying game on
the server
in other news jevin has got in touch and
basically told me that
this is my money now
this is my diamonds he's genuinely
giving it to me
and so i'm going to do the only same
thing i know when i've been given so
many diamonds
and that spend the whole lot on rockets
i get through so many because i fly like
a maniac like
you saw what i did with red i love
flying around like an absolute crazy
person
so we're gonna go straight here
tango's already here all right
[Music]
there we go i might as well keep going
as well
get as many as i can the rate i go
through these seriously so i bought an
entire double chest full already
[Laughter]
that should tide me over for a while
this will last me at least two hours
tango makes so much money from me jevin
really shouldn't have given me all of
that cash because now i'm just gonna
spend it all on rockets
so this is gonna be my emergency supply
for a while
there we go
so that is probably enough
fireworks for at least several hours of
flying for me
so that should be really good and look i
didn't even make a dent in my new money
this is mad i should not be given this
much cash i'll be honest now as many of
you know i have a little secret room
right down here
now this
is the big hole that i made and you
might remember me saying you'll never
know when you need a big hole
and i have come up with exactly what i
want to do here and that is for next
episode but if you want a little sneak
peek into what it might be
wait until the end of this episode there
might be a little bit of a spoiler there
for you
i'm going to create a secret base down
here 100 but what there's gonna be
you will have to wait and find out one
thing is for sure though i'm going to be
using the new technique that i found to
open it so this is the uh this is the
idea this is how it works
so this is how the entrance is gonna
work and if you've watched my most
recent video
then you will already know exactly what
i'm gonna do so basically
so what we have is a pressure plate
hidden behind this place and we could
hide it
here here here anywhere where there's a
decently sized corner we can place this
pressure plate and it's as simple as
throwing the trident in exactly the
right place you get the red zone signal
and what i'm hoping will happen or well
i can make happen is that i create a
floor that opens up and i fall through
into the underground layer so i'm going
to create some sort of mechanism when i
make this and this is what it's going to
be now that i've bought my rockets as
well
this also means that i don't need to
charge that much
i i didn't really even need to change
the price in my stash for cash shop so
i'm going gonna go and put that back to
the way it was because otherwise no one
is ever going to use it again but i feel
like jevin's giving me so much money i
don't need any more sales
so we need to change this from three
stacks of uh
hold on
did that say that says three stacks of
iron
is someone taking the mick three stacks
of
diamonds
there we go now i'm gonna sign this
now nobody can mess with the price
anymore done and dusted
wait i did put that in right didn't i
cool that is exactly what we needed my
base is really starting to look cool now
i can't wait to get this nether portal
in and then i want to mess around with
trying to detail this and i want to
fiddle around trying to fix this bit
because as you can see i have spent like
this was a double chest full of concrete
powder here i've made my way all the way
around but i haven't quite finished yet
this is extraordinarily time consuming
and a lot of resources i'm not even sure
i'm gonna make it all the way around to
create this wall i think i think i might
struggle with that but i'm gonna give it
a go anyway and i think this will look
really cool so that's it for today's
episode thank you very much for watching
everyone i hope you enjoyed it and good
bye